Guide to the Minnie Bruce Pratt Papers, 1870s-2005, bulk 1975-2005 RL.01046
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Teaching Series, 1978-2005 and undated, 10 boxes
  - National Writers' Union workshops, 2004 (2 folders) (Box 112)
  - Job hunt, 2004 January-2005 June (3 folders) (Box 112)
  - The Union Institute correspondence, 2005 (Box 112)
  - National Writers' Union workshop correspondence, 2005 (Box 112)
  - Syracuse University, 2005 (Box 112)
- Financial Material, 1981-2004, 1 boxes
  Material in this series consists of tax returns for the years 1981 to 2004 as well as detailed narratives carefully documenting deductions taken by Pratt related to her writing and teaching career. Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Taxes, 1981-2004 (4 folders) (Box 113)
- Photographs, 1966-2005 and undated, 3 boxes
  Items in this series document events and individuals in Minnie Bruce Pratt's life. Descriptions are provided by Pratt, and arrangement is chronological.
  - Chi Omega pledge class, 1966 (Box 114)
  - Early 1970s (Box 114)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 114)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 114)
  - Thanksgiving, 1977 (Box 114)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 114)
  - Oak Island, 1979 (Box 114)
  - 1979 (Box 114)
  - 1980 (Box 114)
  - Cris South, 1980s (Box 114)
  - 1981 (Box 114)
  - Raleigh, NC, 1981 August-September (Box 114)
  - 1982 (Box 114)
  - Feminary, 1982 (Box 114)
  - Durham, 1982 (Box 114)
  - 1983 (Box 114)
  - 1984 (Box 114)
  - Jacksonville, 1984 May (Box 114)
  - Madison, 1984 July (Box 114)
  - 1985 (Box 114)
  - 1986 (Box 114)
  - LIPS New York, 1986 (Box 114)
  - Ransom's high school graduation, 1986 (Box 114)
  - 1987 (Box 114)
  - 1988 (Box 114)
  - 1989 (Box 114)
  - 1990 (Box 114)
  - Washington, D.C. gay pride parade, 1990 (Box 114)
  - Seattle, 1990 August (Box 114)
  - 1991 (Box 114)
  - 1992 (Box 114)
  - San Francisco, 1992 August (Box 114)
  - 1993 (Box 114)
  - Vieques, Puerto Rico, 1993 January (Box 114)
  - Spring 1993 (Box 114)
  - Women's cultural celebration, April 1993 (Box 114)
  - 1993 May (Box 114)
  - Selma, 1993 July (Box 114)
  - 1993 August (Box 114)
  - 1994 (Box 114)
  - The Names Project, 1994 August (Box 114)
  - Tijuana, 1994 (Box 114)
  - Camp Trans, 1994 (Box 114)
  - 1994 April (Box 114)
  - The Union Institute seminar: Gender Bending, 1994 May (Box 114)
  - Lambda Literary Awards/ABA convention, 1994 May-June (Box 114)
  - Summer 1994 (Box 115)
  - 1994 September (Box 115)
  - The Union Institute commencement, with Carolyn Logan, 1994 October (Box 115)
  - 1995 (Box 115)
  - Interview by German film crew, 1995 October (Box 115)
  - Boston, 1995 March (Box 115)
  - 1995 May (Box 115)
  - New York City and Bradford College (Mass.), 1995 May (Box 115)
  - 1995 September-October (Box 115)
  - Connecticut River, 1995 October (Box 115)
  - Richmond, 1995 November (Box 115)
  - Northampton Pride, 1995 (Box 115)
  - 1995 December-1996 January (Box 115)
  - 1996 (Box 115)
  - The Union Institute seminar, 1996 June (Box 115)
  - Rowing finals Olympics, 1996 (Box 115)
  - Buffalo, New York, 1996 (Box 115)
  - Winston-Salem Pride, 1996 (Box 115)
  - 1997 (Box 115)
  - Chaco Canyon, Spring 1997 (Box 115)
  - Boston Pride, 1997 June (Box 115)
  - 1997 June (Box 115)
  - Germany, 1997 July (Box 115)
  - Cuba, Summer 1997 (Box 115)
  - 1997 December (Box 115)
  - 1997-1999 (Box 115)
  - 1998 (Box 115)
  - Germany, Spring 1998 (Box 115)
  - 1999 (Box 115)
  - West Side YMCA, New York City, 1999 May (Box 115)
  - Ben and Katie's new house, 1999 June (Box 115)
  - Birth of Simon Bruce Kent, 1999 July (Box 115)
  - Simon Bruce Kent, 6 months, 1999 December (Box 115)
  - Solstice, 1999 (Box 115)
  - 2000 (Box 115)
  - West Side YMCA, New York City, Spring 2000 (Box 115)
  - Spring 2000 (Box 115)
  - Ben and Simon, Fall 2000 (Box 115)
  - 147 Chestnut St., 2000 December (Box 115)
  - 2000s (Box 115)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 116)
  - Joan Clingan certification meeting, 2001 January (Box 116)
  - Barry and Rowan, 2001 June (Box 116)
  - Alabama, 2002 July (Box 116)
  - Hamilton College/apartment, 2002-2003 (Box 116)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 116)
  - 2004-2005 (Box 116)
  - undated (Box 116)
  - Oversize photographs (Oversize-box 1)
- Audiovisual Material, 1974-2005 and undated, 5 boxes
  The series contains miscellaneous audiovisual material pertaining to Pratt's speaking engagements, interests, and personal life. The series includes speeches and readings given at gigs, interviews, audio correspondence, programs related to lesbian issues, and instructional materials. Materials are organized into subseries depending on format and include Audio Cassettes, Compact Discs, and Videos.
  RESTRICTED: Interviews are restricted unless permission from the interviewee is obtained.
  - Audio Cassettes, 1974-2005 and undated, 2 boxes
    The subseries comprises speeches, visits to radio programs, lectures, and audio correspondence between Pratt and Joan E. Biren. Additionally, Pratt conducted audio interviews of her grandmother and aunt regarding family secrets, and of friends regarding their experiences coming out as gay, lesbian, or transgender. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject, and Pratt's readings and appearances are arranged chronologically under the heading Pratt, Minnie Bruce. Original label titles were retained, but naming conventions were imposed to keep related materials associated physically. Use copies will need to be created before items can be accessed by researchers.
    - Allison, Dorothy interview, 1995 March 4 (Box 117)
    - Biren, Joan E., NEA Workshop, 1990 August (Box 117)
    - Boyce, Virginia, 1997 March (Box 117)
    - David Duke: An Investigative Report (Box 117)
    - Et Cetera (Box 117)
    - Feinberg, Leslie, Stone Butch Blues, Sophie's Parlor, 1993 January 24 (Box 117)
    - Femme/Butch Radio Broadcast (Box 117)
    - Four Women Creating Themselves (Box 117)
    - Grandma, 1975 January 18 (Box 117)
    - Groddy 9-Toes and Ben Solo (Box 117)
    - The Lannan-just buffalo Writers at Work Series, 1996 (Box 117)
    - MAE IV Lesson 3 (Box 117)
    - North Carolina Women's Conference, Greensboro, 1981 October 10 (Box 117)
    - Out and About: Gay and Lesbian Writing (Box 117)
    - OUT Write Conference, Keynote address by Allen Ginsberg and Judy Grahn (Box 117)
    - Pratt, Minnie Bruce
      - Joan E. Biren and Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1981 September 2-1982 January 15 (8 audio cassettes) (Box 117)
      - Amazon Bookstore, Minneapolis, 1982 April 21 (Box 117)
      - Athens, Ohio, 1982 April 27 (Box 117)
      - Spinsters Ink, New York, 1983 March 26 (Box 117)
      - New Words, Boston, 1983 March 31 (Box 117)
      - A Woman's Story, Deb Morris interview, WPFW/D.C., aired 1983 September 6 (Box 117)
      - Sophie's Parlor, Deb Morris interview, Pacifica/D.C., 1983 October (Box 117)
      - Anti-racism, STWS, 1983 December 4 (2 audio cassettes) (Box 117)
      - Family Secrets lectures, WMST 250, 1984 September 27 (Box 117)
      - Resistance in Everyday Life: Minnie Bruce Pratt, WBAI, 1984 May (Box 117)
      - The Poet and the Poem, WPFW/D.C., 1990 May 13 (Box 117)
    - Pratt, Minnie Bruce
      - Correspondence, Leslie Feinberg and Minnie Bruce Pratt, September 1992-May 1996 (3 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
        Removed to Leslie Box 3.
      - OutWrite Writer's Conference, Public conversation, Minnie Bruce Pratt and Leslie Feinberg, 1993 (Box 118)
      - Vignettes on crossing gender boundaries, Cornell University, 1994 April 21 (2 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
      - New Writing Series, UCSD, 1995 (Box 118)
      - OutWrite, Poetry and Tradition and Opening Plenary Session, 1996 (2 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
      - Interview with Minnie Bruce Pratt and Beth Harrison, Prado, 1997 March 29 (Box 118)
      - Columbia College, 1997 October 18 (Box 118)
      - OutWrite, To Make Revolution Irresistible: Writing, Poetry, and Politics, 1999 February 26-28 (Box 118)
      - OUT FM, 1999 April 18 (Box 118)
      - Infolink, Walking Back Up Depot Street, 1999 May 12 (Box 118)
      - Gender talk, 1999 August 23 (Box 118)
      - Room of One's Own, Madison, Wisconsin, 2003 November 20 (2 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
      - Interview, 2005 April 1 (Box 118)
      - Anti-klan march, undated (Box 118)
      - Fresh Air with Terry Gross, WHYY, undated (Box 118)
      - Plenary III: Closing Address, undated (Box 118)
      - Pratt, Minnie Bruce, Tape 1 and 2, undated (Box 118)
    - President Ford's Message to Congress, 1974 August 12 (2 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
    - President Nixon's Resignation, 1974 August 8 (4 audio cassettes) (Box 118)
    - Sheila, undated (Box 118)
    - Shirley on Louisiana, 1981 (Box 118)
    - South, Cris (Box 118)
  - Compact Discs, 2003 and undated, 1 boxes
    The subseries comprises miscellaneous compact discs, including music, learning tools, and discs related to Pratt's writing. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by title. Use copies will need to be created before items can be accessed by researchers.
    - Consuela Lee, Piano Voices (Box 119)
    - Hip Hop Mix, 2003 April (Box 119)
    - Interactive Glossary for Materials Science and Engineering (Box 119)
    - Introduction to Academic Writing (Box 119)
    - The Laramie Project (Box 119)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt, Voices of Feminism Oral History Project, Sophia Smith Collection (ten CDs) (Box 119)
    - Nedra (Box 119)
    - Ransom Weaver Demo Reel (2 CDs) (Box 119)
    - Triumph of the Human Spirit (Box 119)
    - Women's Voices Radio on WAER Syracuse 88.3 FM (Box 119)
    - Yikes McGee (Box 119)
  - Videos,1986-2000 and undated, 2 boxes
    Arranged alphabetically by title, the Videos subseries primarily contains recordings of Pratt's speaking gigs and programs related to lesbian issues. Use copies will need to be created before items can be accessed by researchers.
    - 1990 National Lesbian's Music Festival, Minnie Bruce Pratt (Box 120)
    - All God's Children (Box 120)
    - Closets are Health Hazards (Box 120)
    - Creating Women's History: The Sophia Smith Collection (Box 120)
    - Dyke TV Show (Box 120)
    - Elian Demo, 2000 January 11 (Box 120)
    - From What to When is (not) Violence: Judith Lombardi (Box 120)
    - In the Life Season Premiere (Box 120)
    - Lesbian Physicians on Practice, Patients and Power (Box 120)
    - Leslie Feinberg and Minnie Bruce Pratt at Emory, 1994 October 7 (Box 120)
    - Making Revolution Irresistible: The Artist's Role in Social Change, Barnard College, 2000 (Box 121)
    - MBP and LF in Florida, 1993 July (Box 121)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt and Cheryl Clarke: Lafayette Presbyterian Church, 1997 June 23 (Box 121)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt Poetry Reading, 1986 March (Box 121)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt S/HE, 1995 October (Box 121)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt, Simpson College, 1999 April 9 (Box 121)
    - Out for a change: Addressing homophobia in women's sports (Box 121)
    - Outlaw (Box 121)
    - Patricia M. Fabiano, Ph.D., The First Thursday Girl's Club: A Narrative Study of Health and Social Support in a Working-Class Community, 2000 October 14 (Box 121)
    - Pratt WALK lunch, 1995 April (Box 121)
    - Peace for Cuba at Symphony Pace (Box 121)
    - Radical Harmonies: The Story of Women's Music (Box 121)
    - Radical Harmonies: Woodstock meets Women's Liberation in a film (Box 121)
    - Straight from the Heart (Box 121)
    - The Wise Ones, Part I (Box 121)
- Printed Material, 1969-2005 and undated, 5 boxes
  The Printed Material series contains periodicals, booklets, printed essays, and chapbooks arranged alphabetically by title. Subjects represented include poetry, women's studies, feminism, lesbianism, and the Ku Klux Klan. Many items include contributions by Pratt or directly relate to her work or projects with which she was involved. A number of periodicals were removed from this collection and added to the Women's and LGBT Movements Periodicals Collection.
  - The Adventures of BK in Exile, vol.1, no.2, 1999 Spring (Box 122)
  - The American Poetry Review, vol.33, no.6, 2004 November-December (Box 122)
  - The American Voice, no.14, 17, 18, 36, 1989-1995 (4 folders) (Box 122)
  - Anchor in the Beet Field, 1999 (Box 122)
  - The Appalachian Anthology, vol.2 and 3, 2003-2004 (2 folders) (Box 122)
  - Art and Letters: Journal of Contemporary Culture, 2004 Autumn (Box 122)
  - Auntie Bellum: A Southern Journal for Women, vol.2, no.1 and 2, 1978 Fall (Box 122)
  - Bad Girls, 1997 (Box 122)
  - Beginning Ballroom Dance, 1995 (Box 122)
  - The Black Woman's Role in the Community of Slaves (Box 122)
  - Bloom, vol.1, no.1, 2004 Winter (Box 122)
  - Bombay Gin, 1997 (Box 122)
  - Boston Piano, 2003 (Box 122)
  - Bridges: A Journal for Jewish Feminists and Our Friends, vol.2, no.1, 1991 Spring (Box 122)
  - Cartographies of Error, 1999 (Box 122)
  - A Case for Equity, 1971 (Box 123)
  - Cat's Eye, no.1 and 2, 1980 Fall-1980 Winter (Box 123)
  - Changing Always, 1981 October (Box 123)
  - Chicago Review, vol.47, no.2, 2001 Summer (Box 123)
  - Clit Rocket, no.2 and 3, 2004 (2 folders) (Box 123)
  - Coal City Review, no.17, 2002 January (Box 123)
  - Conditions: Eight, 1982 (Box 123)
  - Corrections, vol.1, no. 1, 2001 Fall (Box 123)
  - Danielle's Femmetopia, no.1 and 6, 2002 April-September (Box 123)
  - Emerald Pillows, vol.1, no.1-vol.3, no.3, 2003 March-2005 June (2 folders) (Box 123)
  - Emma, 2003 September/October (Box 123)
  - Equal Rights for Women: A Call to Action, 1973 (Box 123)
  - Ethnicity and Politics, 1979 (Box 123)
  - Female Liberation as the Basis for Social Revolution, 1970 February (Box 123)
  - Flannel Morning (Love Songs for Dr. V), 1977 (Box 123)
  - A Framework for Locally Planned Responses to Instances of Racial and Religious Animosity, 1982 (Box 123)
  - Gargoyle, no.41, 1998 (Box 123)
  - The Gay and Lesbian Review, vol.11, no.2, 2004 March-April (Box 123)
  - A Growing Crisis: Disadvantaged Women and Their Children (Box 124)
  - IKON, no.4, 1985 Summer/Winter (Box 124)
  - July Caprice, 1990 (Box 124)
  - Lambda Book Report: A Contemporary Review of Gay and Lesbian Literature, vol.2, no.3, 1990 February-March (Box 124)
  - Literature is Freedom, 2003 (Box 124)
  - Lynching and Rape: An Exchange of Views, 1977 (Box 124)
  - Lynx Eye, vol.11, no.1 and 2, 2004 (2 folders) (Box 124)
  - Ms., 1984 January (Box 124)
  - National Coalition Against Domestic Violence: Women of Color Task Force and Caucus, 1981 (Box 124)
  - The Network, vol.13, 16, 20, 1996-2003 (3 folders) (Box 124)
  - New England Review and Bread Loaf Quarterly, 1983 Summer (2 folders) (Box 124)
  - New England Review, 1995 Spring (Box 124)
  - North Carolina Literary Review, 1999 (Box 125)
  - NWSA Journal, vol.16, no.2, 2004 Summer (Box 125)
  - Ploughshares, 1996 Spring, 2002 Spring (2 folders) (Box 125)
  - The Political Economy of Women's Liberation, 1969 (Box 125)
  - The Politics of Housework (Box 125)
  - Prairie Schooner, 1998, 2004 (2 folders) (Box 125)
  - River Styx: Sweet Dreams and Bad Sex, 1998 (Box 125)
  - A Scarecrow's Bible, 2002 (Box 125)
  - Seneca Review, vol.31, no.1, 2001 (Box 125)
  - Seven Years Later: Women's Studies Programs in 1976, 1977 (Box 125)
  - She: Women's Guide to UNC, 1977 September (Box 125)
  - Sinister Wisdom: Lesbian Mothers and Grandmothers, 2005 Autumn (Box 125)
  - Siren, 2003 (Box 125)
  - Smartish Pace, no.5, 2001 October (Box 126)
  - Socialism, Anarchism, and Feminism (Box 126)
  - Sojourner Truth Organization: Fighting the Klan, 1981 April (Box 126)
  - The Songs of Hiroshima, 1980 (Box 126)
  - Southern Exposure, vol.9, no.2, 1981 Summer (Box 126)
  - The Spoon River Poetry Review, vol.28, no.2, 2003 Summer/Fall (Box 126)
  - Tri-Quarterly, 1997 Fall (Box 126)
  - The Ultimate Dare, 1975 (Box 126)
  - Violence, the Ku Klux Klan, and the Struggle for Equity, 1981 (Box 126)
  - What is the Revolutionary Potential of Women's Liberation?, 1969 (Box 126)
  - The William and Mary Review, vol.40, 2002 (Box 126)
  - Wisconsin Review, vol.39, no.1, 2004 Fall (Box 126)
  - Woman of Power: A Magazine of Feminism, Spirituality, and Politics, no.7, 1987 Summer (Box 126)
  - Women, 1974 (Box 126)
  - Women Workers: The Forgotten Third of the Working Class (Box 126)
  - Women's Liberation and Imperialism (Box 126)
  - Women's Servitude Under Law, 1971 (Box 126)
  - Women's Studies Newsletter, vol.6, no.3, 1978 (Box 126)
  - Working Women for Freedom, 1976 (Box 126)
  - Working Women and Their Organizations-150 Years of Struggle, 1974 (Box 126)
- Ephemera, 1966-2005 and undated, 7 boxes
  The Ephemera series comprises miscellaneous items collected by Pratt and chiefly contains t-shirts, buttons, and posters related to Pratt's activism, the conferences and demonstrations she attended, and Feminary. The Lesbian Sexcapades Parlor Game was invented by Pratt and played while on vacation with JEB, Dee Mosbacher, and Nannette Gartrell. Posters also document Pratt's book relases, speaking appearances, seminars, and courses. The series contains the outfit Pratt wore to the ceremony celebrating the designation of Crime Against Nature as the 1989 Lamont Poetry Selection by the Academy of American Poets. Additional items include candlesticks given to Pratt upon her marriage to Marvin Weaver, a birthday coffee mug from Leslie Feinberg, pens with printed logos, a stamp, and a vibrator and pair of handcuffs given to Pratt by students from Iowa.
  - T-shirts (Box 127)
  - T-shirts (Box 128)
  - Buttons and miscellaneous ephemera (Box 129)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera (Box 130)
  - Banner (Box 131)
  - Rolled posters (Box 132)
  - Rolled posters (Box 133)
  - Flat posters (Box 134)
    Includes poster for Stone Butch Blues release personalized for Pratt by Leslie Feinberg.
  - Lesbian Sexcapades Parlor Game, circa 1984-1989; 9 folders (Box 138)
    General
    Parlor game invented by Minnie Bruce Pratt. The game is played in the form of a round-robin story told by the players in response to prompts found on situation cards and object cards. The situation card lays out the story line of the sexcapade, and each player draws an object card that forms her chapter of the story. The objects range from the erotic to the absurd, and are clipped from magazines and newspapers.